Guide to the Furnifold M. Simmons Papers, 1890-1946
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Furnifold M. Simmons papers 1890-1946
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Simmons, Furnifold M. (Furnifold McLendel), 1854-1940.
33.4 linear feet Extent: 75,000 Items
Furnifold McLendel Simmons (1854-1940) was a U.S. Senator and political leader from North Carolina. Collection contains correspondence (most nearly complete for the 1920s) of Simmons during a large part of his public life. The bulk of the collection deals with such routine political matters as recommendations for appointments, requests for political literature, suggestions for procedure in political campaigns, and special legislation for World War I veterans. Other items relate to reform politics and the orthodox Southern position during Theodore Roosevelt's administration, the Underwood-Simmons tariff, Wilsonian reforms, the financing of World War I, the Southern defection from Alfred E. Smith (1928), and the technique of machine politics. Correspondents include Calvin Coolidge, Herbert Hoover, William Howard Taft, and Woodrow Wilson.
simmonsfurnifold
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Furnifold M. Simmons Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1934.
Biographical Note
Furnifold McLendel Simmons (1854-1940) was a U.S. Senator and political leader from North Carolina.
Collection Overview
Collection contains correspondence (most nearly complete for the 1920s) of Simmons during a large part of his public life. The bulk of the collection deals with such routine political matters as recommendations for appointments, requests for political literature, suggestions for procedure in political campaigns, and special legislation for World War I veterans. Other items relate to reform politics and the orthodox Southern position during Theodore Roosevelt's administration, the Underwood-Simmons tariff, Wilsonian reforms, the financing of World War I, the Southern defection from Alfred E. Smith (1928), and the technique of machine politics. Correspondents include Calvin Coolidge, Herbert Hoover, William Howard Taft, and Woodrow Wilson.
Addition contains primarily correspondence and clippings relating to the senatorial career of Simmons, especially his opposition to Al Smith in 1928 and his electoral defeat in 1930. Two of the letters are in regard to suffrage in North Carolina. Also includes a large number of obituaries (1940).
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933; Democratic Party (N.C.); Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Legislators -- United States -- Correspondence; North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Patronage, Political -- United States; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1928; Progressivism (United States politics); Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Simmons, Furnifold M. (Furnifold McLendel), 1854-1940; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944; Southern States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Suffrage -- North Carolina; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Tariff -- Law and legislation -- United States; United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1933.; United States. Congress. Senate -- Elections; Veterans -- Law and legislation -- United States; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; World War, 1914-1918 -- Finance -- United States
Contents of Collection
- Furnifold M. Simmons Papers, 1890-1946, (78 boxes)
  - Correspondence: 1990-1908. Feb.15 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: 1908, Feb. 15 - 1909, March 10 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: 1909, March 11 - 1909, June 30 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: 1909, July 1 - 1910, Jan. 31 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: 1910, Feb. 1 - 1910, March 24 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: 1910, March 25 - 1910, June 10 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: 1910, June 2 - 1915, December (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: 1916 - 1918, July 27 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: 1918, July 28 - 1918, Oct. 21 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: 1918, Oct. 22 - 1918, Dec. 20 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: 1918, Dec. 21 - 1919, Feb. 10 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: 1919, Feb. 11 - 1919, March 20 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: 1919, March 21 - 1919, May 10 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: 1919, May 11 - 1919, June 30 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: 1919, July 1 - 1919, July 31 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: 1919, Aug. 1 - 1919, Sept. 22 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: 1919, Sept. 23 - 1919, Nov. 5 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: 1919, Nov. 6 - 1920, Jan. 5 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: 1920, Jan. 6 - 1920, Feb. 14 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: 1920, Feb. 15 - 1920, March 28 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: 1920, March 29 - 1920, May 12 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: 1920, May 13 - 1920, June 30 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: 1920, July 1 - 1920, Aug. 31 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: 1920, Sept. 1 - 1920, Oct. 30 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: 1920, Nov. 1 - 1920, Dec. 31 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: 1921, Jan. 1 - 1921, Feb. 13 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence: 1921, Feb. 14 - 1921, April 5 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: 1921, April 6 - 1921, May 15 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence: 1921, May 15 - 1921, June 30 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: 1921, July 1 - 1921, Aug. 12 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: 1921, Aug. 13 - 1921, Sept. 19 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: 1921, Sept. 20 - 1920, Oct. 18 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence: 1921, Oct. 19 - 1921, Nov. 27 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence: 1921, Nov. 28 - 1921, Dec. 31 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence: 1922, Jan. 1 - 1922, March 13 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence: 1922, March 14 - 1922, May 31 (Box 36)
  - Correspondence: 1922, June 1 - 1922, Aug. 17 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence: 1922, Aug. 18 - 1922, Oct. 31 (Box 38)
  - Correspondence: 1922, Nov. 1 - 1923, Feb. 10 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: 1923, Feb. 11 - 1923, April 31 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence: 1923, May 1 - 1923, July 16 (Box 41)
  - Correspondence: 1923, July 17 - 1923, Oct. 16 (Box 42)
  - Correspondence: 1923, Oct. 17 - 1923, Dec. 31 (Box 43)
  - Correspondence: 1924, Jan. 1 - 1924, Feb. 15 (Box 44)
  - Correspondence: 1924, Feb. 16 - 1924, March 31 (Box 45)
  - Correspondence: 1924, April 1 - 1924, May 15 (Box 46)
  - Correspondence: 1924, May 16 - 1924, July 23 (Box 47)
  - Correspondence: 1924, July 24 - 1924, Oct. 15 (Box 48)
  - Correspondence: 1924, Oct. 16 - 1924, Dec. 13 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence: 1924, Dec. 14 - 1925, Feb. 12 (Box 50)
  - Correspondence: 1925, Feb. 13 - 1925, April 30 (Box 51)
  - Correspondence: 1925, May 1 - 1925, Aug. 31 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: 1925, Sept. 1 - 1925, Dec. 18 (Box 53)
  - Correspondence: 1925, Dec. 19 - 1926, Jan. 31 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence: 1926, Feb. 1 - 1926, March 15 (Box 55)
  - Correspondence: 1926, March 16 - 1926, April 30 (Box 56)
  - Correspondence: 1926, May 1 - 1926, June 31 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence: 1926, July 1 - 1926, Sept. 30 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence: 1926, Oct. 1 - 1926, Dec. 17 (Box 59)
  - Correspondence: 1926, Dec. 18 - 1927, Feb 9 (Box 60)
  - Correspondence: 1927, Feb 10 - 1927, April 15 (Box 61)
  - Correspondence: 1927, April 16 - 1927, Sept. 30 (Box 62)
  - Correspondence: 1927, Oct. 1 - 1928, Jan. 31 (Box 63)
  - Correspondence: 1928, Feb 1 - 1928, May 31 (Box 64)
  - Correspondence: 1928, June 1 - 1928, Aug. 31 (Box 65)
  - Correspondence: 1928, Sept. 1 - 1928, Dec 31 (Box 66)
  - Correspondence: 1929, Jan. 1 - 1929, April 30 (Box 67)
  - Correspondence: 1929, May 1 - 1929, Aug. 31 (Box 68)
  - Correspondence: 1929 Sept. 1 - 1929, Nov. 30 (Box 69)
  - Correspondence: 1929 Dec. 1 - 1930, Feb. 14 (Box 70)
  - Correspondence: 1930, Feb. 15 - 1930, April 6 (Box 71)
  - Correspondence: 1930, April 7 - 1930, May 31 (Box 72)
  - Correspondence: 1930, June 1 - 1930, Dec. 31 (Box 73)
  - Correspondence: 1931 - 1939, Jan. and n.d. (Box 74)
  - Press Release; Legal Papers, Financial Papers, Invitations and Cards, Photographs; Broadsides; New Bern Resort Papers; Memorial Exercise (Box 74)
  - General Files: Agriculture Services (Box 75)
  - General Files: Tariffs - Veterans - Politics (Box 76)
  - Annotated volumes of the Congressional Record (Box 77)
  - Annotated volumes of the Congressional Record (Box 78)